FAVIAN MEDINA

Web developer

CONTACT

- +591-67023053
- <u>favian.medina.gemio@gmail.com</u>
- **Q** La Paz Bolivia South America
- https://favian-medinacv.vercel.app/index en.html
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/favian-medina-35a5471a4/

EDUCATION

2003

UNIVERSIDAD MAYOR DE SAN ANDRÉS (UMSA)

Bachelor's Degree in Computer
Science
2016

PLURINATIONAL SCHOOL OF PUBLIC MANAGEMENT (EGPP)

 Diploma in Free Software and GNU/LINUX

2021

LINUX PROFESSIONAL INSTITUTE (LPI)

 101-500 Linux Administrator y LE-1 Linux Essentials.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, PHP, nodeJS, APi-Rest, Json, Git, MS WINDOWS, Docker, Proxmox, PostgrSQL, MySQL, MS Sql Server, Oracle, EasyUI, Excel, VueJS, AngularJs

Teamwork,

Problem solving,

Proactivity,

Continuous learning

LANGUAJES

- English: B1 Intermedium
- French: Basic
- Spanish: Native language, full professional proficiency

PROFILE

Extensive experience in the IT field for nearly 17 years, specializing in web application development, data analysis for public entities in Bolivia, and recently in the technical support area. Proficient in troubleshooting and delivering excellent customer service.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pension and Insurance Supervisory and Control 2012-2017 Authority (APS).

SENIOR EPI COORDINATION PROFESSIONAL (Back End)

- Development of queries, generation of statistics and creation of control reports in MS SQL Server and Oracle databases, ensuring consistency and accuracy of information to facilitate analysis and decision making in Project Management (PD).
- Process management through data analysis and queries in MS SQL Server, MySQL and PostgreSQL databases for the monitoring of Claims Synchronization, Dignity Income (RD) payment reconciliation, Disbursements and Actuarial Value of the RD system.
- Execution of data crosswalks in the Actuarial Value database using MS SQL Server, ensuring consistency of information.
- Management of a team of 13 people for the supervision of processes related to payments, claims and funeral expenses in the DR system.
- Coordination and supervision of the (multi-disciplinary) team in charge of home payment assignments, funeral expenses and claims management, ensuring smooth communication and efficient execution.
- Collaborative, results-oriented management and decision making by supervising a team of 13 employees, with a focus on meeting goals related to home payments, funeral expenses and Renta Dignidad claims.
- Execution of database queries to assign goals in the claims synchronization process, ensuring the timely fulfillment of Renta Dignidad payments (RD)

Ministry of Development Planning

2011-2012

ConsultING (full stack developer)

- Development and maintenance of SISIN system modules using PostgreSQL, MySQL and PHP, improving the data management of the Vice-Ministry of Planning and Public Investment (VIPFE).
- Analysis and design of modules for the Plurinational State Information System (SIEP), ensuring efficiency and scalability through optimized database queries.

Ministry of Finance

2004-2009

Consulting (full stack developer)

- Development and maintenance, migration of the Human Resources system, with Vacation, Personnel Control and Refreshments modules, using JavaScript, PHP and MS SQL Server to efficiently manage human resources processes (migration from Delphi desktop to web platform).
- Administration of network services such as email (ms exchange), web site, proxy server, databases (mysql/ms sql server) and FTP services, ensuring their availability and performance in the corporate environment.
- Development and maintenance of web reports of the SICOES system, implementing data capture forms and information search engines, using JavaScript, PHP and Oracle to improve the efficiency of the public management procurement system.